<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on krismorte</title><link>https://krismorte.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on krismorte</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 18:55:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://krismorte.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Managing your github account with terraform</title><link>https://krismorte.github.io/posts/managing-github-terraform/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 18:55:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://krismorte.github.io/posts/managing-github-terraform/</guid><description>It’s well known that GIT is essential to any company that handle, in any level, some code and cloud solution as well as github, gitlab and bitbucket, mostly these days. Today I will tell you a little about the pain that is to manage repositories and their permissions, and why I ended up adopting terraform to manager my github.
As the company grows the same happens with git repositories growing exponentially and the lack of pattern spreads like a disease and of course the risk to some information leak becomes a reality.</description></item><item><title>AWS RDS Backup Strategy</title><link>https://krismorte.github.io/posts/aws-rds-backup-strategy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 18:55:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://krismorte.github.io/posts/aws-rds-backup-strategy/</guid><description>This post will talk about backup and disaster recovery strategy on AWS RDS been mande by lambdas. First of all let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the default snapshot that comes enable on every RDS and from my sight is a really good solution with its point-in-time option that takes log backups each every 5 minutes which allow us huge coverage on failures. There&amp;rsquo;s 2 types of snapshot automated and manual, automated are taken daily and incremented all day long to delivery the point-in-time solution these snapshot are holding for 35 days max, and this isn&amp;rsquo;t configurable, the manual are made manually, throuth the CLI or by application and there&amp;rsquo;s no expire date and are limited to 100 per instance and region but you can increase this number opening a support ticket with AWS.</description></item><item><title>Documenting Databases With Schemaspy</title><link>https://krismorte.github.io/posts/documenting-databases-with-schemaspy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 18:55:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://krismorte.github.io/posts/documenting-databases-with-schemaspy/</guid><description>When I think about database&amp;rsquo;s documentation remember me of centralizing tools where everything about databases was born on the DBA&amp;rsquo;s hands, design, to chaneg a columntype was needed open a ticket and thing like that. In a world without migrations and CI\CD makes totally sense give that power to the right guy, huge databases with tons of objects and data somethime attend more than one sysmte at time make us need a benevolent dictator.</description></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>https://krismorte.github.io/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 20:32:37 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://krismorte.github.io/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>My first publication is more &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; this blog and going directly to the point is to share experience and knowledge in this fast change tech world. A lot of people who I&amp;rsquo;ve been following always said the same thing shared knowledge, write about your experience and the environment that you experienced and which tecnologies are you using today and now I&amp;rsquo;m starting my own jorney here.
This is not my first blog, I really like to write, my first blog still on-line and was about shows and rock bands in my home town, because of my lack of time I ended for leaving but if you wanna take a look rock-ce.</description></item></channel></rss>